Mohammed Alhato

Leeds (open to relocation) | Eligible to work in the UK without sponsorship | 07466880586 mh.alhato@alumni.lse.ac.uk | GitHub | LinkedIn

Problem Solver | Team Player | Tech Enthusiast

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Growing up in Gaza, the opportunities to enter the tech field were limited. However, I had always had a passion for computing. The way technology can solve real-world problems has always fascinated me and drives me to continually upskill myself to keep up with emerging technologies. I am a highly motivated and results-oriented AWS Re/Start graduate with a passion for cloud computing services. My experience in project management has led me to excel in problem-solving, lateral thinking and collaboration with multiple stakeholders. I am experienced in using various AWS services in the areas of Compute, Storage, Security, Databases, and Networking. My ambition is to develop and transfer my skills to an established career in cloud computing.

KEY TECH SKILLS

- **Linux:** Administrating Linux environments, troubleshooting and managing users, and system administration in Linux by using the command line and deploying EC2 instances
- AWS: Solid understanding of cloud computing service models (laaS, PaaS, SaaS) and AWS services such as EC2, RDS, S3, and AWS Lambda
- Networking: Ipv4 addressing, subnetting and CIDR, OSI model, internet and routing protocols, and troubleshooting
- **Security:** Experienced in developing custom VPC's and deploying EC2 instances focusing on network security and configuration
- Python Programming: Writing and executing Python scripts on a Linux machine to interact with the underlying operating system, users, and storage and understanding how to write scripts to automate tasks and interact with a MySQL database
- Databases: Understanding the design and implementation of a relational database and running SQL queries on a MySQL database. Creating and maintaining a relational database, writing custom functions to aid in querying. Understanding the design and implementation of NoSQL databases such as AWS DynamoDB
- Version Control and other skills: Using Git/GitHub, VS code, Slack and Discord.
 Using WinSCP, Putty, RDP to access virtual machines between Windows and Linux environments. Using Linux distributions including CentOS and Ubuntu

EXPERIENCE

AWS re/Start Trainee (Full-Time)

August 2021 - Present

Generation UK & Ireland | Leeds

- Completed an intense full-time 12-week classroom-based training programme on AWS cloud and acquired the AWS Cloud Practitioner Certification
- Learned how to apply core AWS services in compute, storage, and networking, including EC2, S3, IAM, VPC, Lambda, Cloud Formation, RDS, and Route 53

- Developed IT fundamental skills, including sufficient knowledge of Linux OS, writing scripts in Python and Bash
- Employed excellent programming fundamentals with Python to create scripts for AWS.
- Designed and developed MySQL databases, running SQL queries and inserting encrypted user input using a Python program written independently
- Collaborated in teams, as well as individually, to problem solve and complete hands-on technical labs

ICT Teaching Assistant (Volunteer)

May 2021 - August 2021

Leeds Refugee Forum | Leeds

- Supported refugees to develop knowledge and confidence in using online applications and improve their digital skills, including Microsoft packages and Zoom software
- Prepared responsive and adaptable learning content for each learner's level and context
- Established effective communication and collaborated with other staff members and volunteers to guarantee optimal support for the service users

Project Assistant (Full-Time)

August 2018 - September 2019

Pal-Think for Strategic Studies | Palestine

- Generated 100% accurate and timely weekly and monthly narrative reports for the project manager, coordinator, and donors
- Maintained the company electronic database and performed data entry functions regularly
- Prepared correspondence and presentations and provided follow-up for verbal and written communications
- Created data collection tools and conducted data analysis and reporting using MS Excel and SPSS to drive conclusions from +20 project and research surveys

EDUCATION

The London School of Economics and Political Science September 2019 - September 2020 MSc Human Resources and Organisations (Full-Time)

Grade: High Merit | Field project on how project managers' personality impacts project success.

University of Delaware & Georgetown University (USA) June 2018 - August 2018 Student Leaders Programme (Cultural Exchange) - funded by the US State Department

Islamic University of Gaza (Palestine)

September 2014 - May 2018

Bachelor of Business Administration - BBA

• Graduated with a GPA of 91.27% (Distinction) | Erasmus+ Programme in Spain

INTERESTS

- Football: Team captain (3 years) and the best striker during secondary school
- Blogging: Volunteered to write business blogs in Arabic at http://keefwiki.com/business/author/mohammedhato/ and have a tech blog hosted my personal website.